JOEL ROCHA

☑ joelxr@gmail.com ♀ joelxr in joelxr ♀ joelxr.github.io

10+ years of experience in software development, strong analytical skills and knowledge of the full software development life cycle, worked for many dynamic and successful companies. Proactive, communicative.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Cardea Project, Co-founder, June/2017 - Today

Co-creating a solution to handle appointment scheduling and billing of physiotherapy clinics. Developing features based on the customer's needs. Designing a web application using Vue framework. Working on an API with Express, Go and MongoDB. (Vue.js, Webpack, Bootstrap3, REST, Node, Express, Golang, MongoDB, NoSQL).

Instituto Atlântico C, Software Engineer, July/2020 - Today

Evolving a voice assistant solution for a global printer manufacturer. Creating skills in Python (for Alexa devices) and Javascript (for Google devices). Integrating with API for low-level communication. Developing a new authentication flow using OAuth2. Deploying with AWS Elastic Beanstalk and CI/CD with Jenkins. Integrating my team with two other independent teams, leadership experience mentoring new members. (Javascript, Express, Node.js, Python, Ruby, Docker, AWS).

Casa Magalhães 2, Frontend Leader, January/2019 - July/2020

Leading frontend developers team. Developing a redesign for a solution to retailers. Designing an architecture to keep old and new features in the same SPA, enabling us to deliver new features using Vue and the old ones stayed intact. Close to a UI/UX team to build a Design System. Teaching frontend technologies to the team. (Vue.js, Vuex, Axios, Jest, SCSS, CSS Modules, Cypress, Webpack).

Municipal Bureau of Finance of Ceará State 3, Software Engineer, April/2016 - December, 2018

Developing solutions to improve all city needs in light of municipal taxes. Creating an engine to read gigabytes of payments and debts files. Creating pages to provide feedback on background tasks. (Java, JBoss Seam, Maven, EJB, Hibernate, Oracle, JSF, Richfaces, jQuery, Bootstrap3)

CPQi C, Software Engineer, November/2012 - April/2016

Developing integrations with third-party systems using messages and queues. Implementing Calypso (v14) for Futures, Fixed Income, and SWAPs products. Covering Brazilian interest rate and inflation indices for the Sao Paulo stock exchange. (Calypso, Java, JSF, EL, Web Services, Web Sockets, JUnit, Mule ESB, Oracle, SQL Server, IBM MQ, FIX Protocol).

Ebix 7, Software Engineer, April/2009 - November/2012

Maintaining solutions to the leading insurance companies in Brazil. Working on new features and fixes. Close to the clients. (Java, JSP, MVC, Javascript, Oracle, SQL Server, Web Services, SOA, JDBC, Hibernate, JSF, jQuery).

EDUCATION

Computer Engineering, BSc., 2015 Instituto Federal de Educação, Ciência e Tecnologia do Ceará 🗗

CERTIFICATES LANGUAGES

freeCodeCamp 2020 Responsive Web
freeCodeCamp 2020 Javascript Algorithms And Data Structures
MongoDB 2017 MongoDB for Node.js Developers
Oracle 2016 Java SE 6 Programmer

Portuguese Native English Advanced Spanish Intermediate